Hey there, tech enthusiasts.
If you've been keeping
an eye on the
AI landscape,
you know that Chatchy
PT is revolutionizing how
we interact with technology.
Now, the way we
develop apps is changing
drastically.
It is no longer
just about code and
design.
In fact, Alpic has
shared some incredible lessons
from their journey in
building
Chatchy PT apps that
you won't want to
miss.
Let's dive right into
the core of these
lessons.
First up is the
idea of AI first
experiences.
Unlike traditional applications which
focus heavily
on UI workflows, Chatchy
PT apps prioritize interaction
with AI models.
This shift means developers
need to rethink how
they structure their applications.
One of the biggest
challenges developers face
is managing the flow
of information between the
user, UI and the
model, traditional web patterns.
Like just in time,
data fetching can actually
hurt the user experience
in these apps.
It's crucial to design
around the AI's capabilities
rather than against them.
So how can you
get started?
Alpic has created an
open source framework called
Skybridge
that incorporates all these
lessons into a user
-friendly format.
This is a game
changer for developers
looking to build efficient
Chatchy PT apps.
Additionally, a codex skill
has been developed to
streamline the process of
ideation, building, testing and
shipping your app.
In conclusion,
building Chatchy PT apps
is a different beast
compared to traditional development.
It requires a fresh
perspective on app structure
and user interaction.
If you're ready to
embrace this AI first
approach, these lessons from
Alpic will
pave the way for
your success.
Thanks for watching, and
don't forget to like
and subscribe for more
tech insights.