So you want to
run a local LLM,
but you have no
idea which model will
actually work
on your hardware.
You Google around, download
a 70 billion parameter
model,
and watch your GPU
cry as it chokes
on VRAM.
We've all been there,
but what if there
was a tool
that could scan your
system,
analyze 266 different models
from 57 providers,
and tell you exactly
which ones will run
smoothly?
That is exactly what
LMF it does,
and it is about
to save you hours
of frustration.
LMF it automatically detects
your system's RAM, CPU,
and GPU capabilities.
The moment you run
it, no manual config
needed.
Then here is the
cool part.
It scores every single
model across four dimensions,
quality, speed, fit, and
context.
The fit score is
particularly brilliant
because it tells you
not just if a
model will run,
but how well it'll
perform on your specific
hardware.
It handles mixture of
experts, architectures,
multi -GPU setups, and
even accounts
for dynamic quantization options.
This means you get
realistic speed estimates,
not just theoretical ones.
By default, LMF it
boots you into an
interactive
two -way, think retro
-futuristic terminal interface
with actual usability.
You scroll through models,
see their scores at
a glance,
and pick one that
fits.
But here is the
thing.
If you prefer the
classic command line experience,
there is a climb
mode too.
The integration with Alama
means once you find
a model
you like, you can
download it directly from
within the tool.
No need to jump
between apps.
Windows users get dedicated
install instructions too.
So nobody's left out.
The local LM space
is exploding right now,
but hardware fragmentation is
a real problem.
Your RTX 4000 and
90 can handle things
that would brick a
360.
LMBIT solves this by
giving you data -driven
recommendations
instead of guesswork.
206 models from 57
providers
that is an insane
amount of variety
to sort through manually.
And the sister project,
CUBEclaw handles
Kubernetes agent management.
If you are running
things at scale,
this is enterprise great
thinking applied
to a personal problem.
Installation is stupid, simple
curl,
home brew, or cargo,
take your pick, run
the tool,
let it scan your
hardware and get instant
answers.
No more downloading models,
only to find out
they won't fit in
your VRAM.
No more trial and
error,
just solid recommendations based
on
what your machine can
actually handle.
Drop a comment if
you've tried LLMBIT
and what model it
recommended for you.
I am curious what
others are running
and subscribe if you
want more local AI
content
because this space is
moving fast.