Okay, here's something wild.
There's a new AI
model claiming to be
the first frontier model
with
intelligence to cheap to
meter, and it's priced
at just $1 per
hour.
That's less than your
morning
coffee.
Meet MiniMax M2 .5,
the latest from the
Chinese AI startup that's
been quietly crushing
benchmarks while everyone was
watching Open AI and
Anthropic.
But here's the plot
twist.
The real world performance
might not match the
marketing.
Let's dig in.
Let's talk numbers.
MiniMax is claiming some
seriously impressive stats.
On SWE Bench Verified,
that's the gold
standard for coding ability.
M2 .5 scores 80
.2%.
That's competitive with Claude
Opus 4 .6,
and it's 37 %
faster than their own
M2 .1 model.
They're also hitting 51
.3 % on multi
SWE Bench,
and 76 .3 %
on Browse Comp, which
tests real web search
capabilities.
The artificial analysis
intelligence index, a score
of 42, way above
the industry average of
26, and with a
205K token
context window, this thing
can handle massive documents
without breaking a sweat.
The pricing is aggressive,
$1 per hour at
100 tokens per second,
or just $0 .30
per hour at half
speed.
Now here's where it
gets interesting.
Independent users on Reddit
are calling BS on
the hype.
They're reporting hallucination issues
and poor online search
utilization compared to rivals
like Kimmy 2 .5
and GLM5.
Some testers found it
actually underperformed expectations set
by the
benchmarks, with one user
noting it fell below
HIKU 4 .5 in
practical testing.
On the plus side,
it does show strong
architectural planning skills.
It tends to write
specs before coding,
which developers actually love.
And multilingual coding?
Impressive.
But that verbosity issue
is real.
Generating 56 million tokens
versus an industry average
of 15
million means you're paying
for a lot of
extra words.
So what's the verdict?
If you're building
something that matches exactly
what these benchmarks test,
pure coding, structured agentic
tasks,
big document processing, M2
.5 at that price
point is genuinely compelling.
It's fast,
it's capable, and frankly
the pricing is disruptive.
But if you need
reliable real -time search
or
can't tolerate hallucinations in
production, you might want
to wait for version
2 .6 or look
at
competitors.
The gap between benchmark
heaven and real -world
usability is real.
That's your
signal to test it
yourself before committing.
Hit subscribe if you
want more unfiltered AI
model breakdowns.
I'll see you in
the next one.