Did you know you
can create a fully
functional AI
telephony agent in minutes?
It's true.
VideoSK lets you build
agents that handle both
inbound
and outbound calls.
Imagine the possibilities ready
to dive in.
First, you need Python
3 .12 or higher
than sign up for
free.
VideoSK account to get
your VideoSK account token.
You'll also need a
SIP provider like Twilio
to direct calls to
VideoSK.
Let's build that AI
agent start with the
main Pi file.
That's where the magic
happens.
Use routing rules to
dispatch calls to your
self -hosted agent.
Don't forget the requirements,
TXT, or your Python
packages.
What powers this setup?
It's all about the
architecture.
SIP providers connect calls
to VideoSK's robust telephony
infrastructure.
This allows seamless call
handling and intelligent routing.
And with your NV
file, your credentials stay
safe.
So are you ready
to unleash the power
of AI and telephony?
Start building your agent
today.
The future of communication
is here.
Don't miss out on
this game -changing technology.